# Adrián López Calvo

## Software Engineer

Calle de Lerida 30, 28020, Madrid, Madrid Spain

□ adrian.lc.work@gmail.com □ +34 676 789 447



Experience on *backend* web development, databases and micro services. I'm the most familiar with the *Python* ecosystem with a preference for open source tools.

Things I love to work with include: APIs, testing, continuous integration, databases and performance tuning

#### SKILLS

#### **Programming**

Advanced

python | go | java | ruby | javascript | git | testing

#### **Backend**

Advanced

django | celery | sql | postgresql | mysql | mongodb | kafka | elasticsearch | web services | distributed micro services | scrapping

#### **DevOps**

Intermediate

ansible | docker | kubernetes | vagrant | continuous integration | amazon web services | google cloud | travis | gitlab ci

#### **Frontend**

Beginner

html | vue | django & jinja templates | css | jquery

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer at Datadog

July 2020 - Current

https://www.datadoghq.com/

Skills acquired: go | java | python | kafka | postgresql | micro services | grpc

I joined after acquisition of Undefined Labs to build the new product for CI Visibility.

- Built and evolved the data ingestion pipeline for CI webhooks.
- Designed a common data model for data from the different CI systems in the market.
- Main responsible for the integrations of the CI Visibility product with Gitlab, CircleCI and Azure DevOps.
- Built a service to ingest jUnit XML test exports. This makes use of a streaming parser that minimizes memory usage.
- Rewrote a big part of the PostgreSQL schema and queries, with better normalized tables and pre-aggregating results to fix latency
  issues on the APIs. The latency improvements were huge and it fixed most of the reliability issues.
- Conducted coding interviews to help grow the team and I also mentored interns and new engineers.

### Software Engineer at Undefined Labs

May 2019 - July 2020

https://undefinedlabs.com

Skills acquired: python | django | postgresql | graphql | postgresql

I joined as the only backend engineer in cooperation with the CTO, to build a new SaaS product for visibility on Flaky tests and CI.

- Evolved and maintained the GraphQL API. This was the core used by the React frontend of the product.
- Optimized recursive SQL queries with PostgreSQL to iterate the Git branches as in Git log.
- Maintained the data ingestion code supporting SDK engineers. The data was ingested from SDKs to PostgreSQL.
- Adding Dataloaders to the GraphQL API to improve latency of the app.

#### Software Engineer at Cabify

December 2017 - May 2019

https://cabify.com

Skills acquired: python | ruby | vue | elixir | mysql | docker | kubernetes | gce | google pubsub

I kick-started the Internal Tools team working on internal features for logistics and marketing departments.

- Built a service to delete and anonymize user data in compliance with European regulations.
- Developed a service to give out price discounts in mass to user segments targeted by marketing.
- Mentored less experienced engineers that joined the team.

### Backend Developer at HundredRooms

June 2016 - September 2017

https://hundredrooms.com

Skills acquired: python | celery | scrapy | asyncio | mysql | mongodb | ansible | docker | kubernetes | gce | grafana

Worked on getting the data processing core of the product to the next level.

- Migrated a big part of the systems from in-house servers to the cloud with Ansible.
- Moved most of them to Docker and a Kubernetes cluster.
- Established a reliable deployment process and adequate testing tools.
- Implemented real time data synchronization between MongoDB and MySQL.
- Integrated external data into the platform through several APIs and scraping.
- Developed asynchronous components of the system with Asyncio.
- Upgraded a huge part of the code base from Python 2 to 3.
- Worked on improving the database schema.

## Software Engineer at Smartvel

October 2014 - June 2016

https://smartvel.com

Skills acquired: python | django | django-rest-framework | celery | postgresql | postgis | redis | mongodb | elasticsearch | ansible | vagrant | aws

Built products of the company focusing mostly on backend and web development.

- Migrated the processing core to an asynchronous queue system with Celery.
- Managed the work queues: routing, priorities, monitoring, concurrency, autoscaling, deployments.

- Built a component to translate texts, obtained through scrapping, automatically.
- Implemented several tools to improve names and boundaries in the geographic data.
- Maintained geographic boundaries with QGIS and shapefiles.
- Set up the MongoDB server with Ansible.
- Handled several major upgrades such as: MongoDB 2 to 3, Django 1.7 to 1.9 or Rest Framework 2 to 3.
- Optimized critical SQL queries, including Postgresql extensions such as postgis, trigrams and full text search.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Scrum Coaching** at Agilar Consultancy 2017 - 2017

## **BS Computer Science** at Universidade de Santiago de Compostela

Major courses: oo programming | data structures & algorithms | software engineering | operative systems | networks | system administration | web development | web services | distributed computing

LANGUAGES ———			
<b>Spanish</b> native speaker	<b>English</b> advanced	Galician native speaker	
REFERENCES —			

Available upon request.